Essex Company Photographs 6633 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- P 217.604-.612 -- Photos of frozen waterfall, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Item 5: View of Essex Company's Dam, 1905; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Item 6: View of Essex Company's Dam, 1905; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Item 7: View of Essex Company's Dam, 1905; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Item 8: View of Essex Company's Dam, 1905; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Item 9: View of Essex Company's Dam, 1905; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 4)
- P 217.574-.584 -- Foster Ledge (Nov. 14, 1876); Island Pond, Derry, NH (July 3, 1905) + (June 5, 1905); Moran accident, Lawrence Gas Co.'s Pit (Jan. 28, 1899), 1876-1905 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: View showing scene of Moran accident, 1899; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 5)
    Lawrence Gas Company's Pit, January 28, 1899
  - Item 2: View showing scene of Moran accident, 1899; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Item 3: View of old dam, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 5)
    Head gates and new dam in process of construction, Island Pond, Derry, NH
  - Item 4: View of down stream side of wasteway, 1905; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 5)
    With about 6" flash board on crest. Island Pond, Derry, NH, July 3, 1905
  - Item 5: Longfellow Bridge, Boston, Mass., 1905; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 5)
    View of upper side of wasteway, Island Pond, Derry, NH, July 3, 1905
  - Item 6: View of upper side of regulating gate and dam, 1905; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 5)
    Island Pond, Derry, NH, July 3, 1905
  - Item 7: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Item 8: View of Essex Company's Central Ledge, 1876; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 5)
    November 14, 1876.
  - Item 9: View of Essex Company's Central Ledge, 1876; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Item 10: View of Essex Company's Foster Ledge, 1876; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Item 11: View of Essex Company's Foster Ledge, 1876; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 5)
- P 217.585-.603 -- Original Whittier Homestead (1907); Essex Co., North Canal (July 27, 1902), 1902-1907 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Cabinet card photo "Seal of Andover Bridge", black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Item 2: View of Original Whittier Homestead, 1907; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 6)
    Copyright 1907 by W. A. Morse
  - Item 3: View of Original Whittier Homestead, 1907; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Item 4: View of Original Whittier Homestead, 1907; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Item 5: View of Original Whittier Homestead, 1907; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Item 6: Unidentified, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Item 7: Unidentified, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Item 8: Unidentified photo of ship model, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Item 9: Unidentified photo of ship model, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Item 10: View of head gates at North Canal, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 6)
    From inside Canal which is drained
  - Item 11: View of head gates at North Canal, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Item 12: View of head gates at North Canal, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Item 13: View of head gates at North Canal, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Item 14: View of head gates at North Canal, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Item 15: View of head gates at North Canal, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Item 16: View of head gates at North Canal, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Item 17: View of No. 4 Essex Company North Canal, 1902; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 6)
    July 27, 1902, looking upstream showing Southerly half of enlarging mouth pieces. Sluiceways at entrance to Canal.
  - Item 18: View of No. 4 Essex Company North Canal, 1902; black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 6)
    July 27, 1902, looking upstream showing general arrangement of enlarging mouth pieces at sluiceways, entrance to canal. Surface of water at about (20.5)
  - Item 19: View of head gates at North Canal, black and white photograph (Box 14, Folder 6)
- P 217.248.322; 217.459 -- Munroe Felt + Paper Co.; Washington Mills Co., 1895-1902 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: View of Everett Mills Wheel No. 3, 27" Hercules, 1920; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
    November 24, 1920.
  - Item 2: View of Everett Mills 39" Hercules Wheel, "Type D", 1920; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
    December 18, 1920.
  - Item 3: View of Everett Mills 39" Hercules Wheel, "Type D", 1920; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 4: View of Everett Mills 39" Hercules Wheel, "Type D", 1920; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 5: View of Everett Mills 39" Hercules Wheel, "Type D", 1920; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 6: View of Everett Mills Wheel No. 2, "G" 27" R. H. Hercules, 1920; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 7: View of Everett Mills 39" Hercules Wheel, "Type D", 1920; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 8: View of Everett Mills Wheel No. 2, "G" 27" R. H. Hercules, 1920; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 9: View of Everett Mills 39" Hercules Wheel, "Type D", 1920; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 10: View of Everett Mills 39" Hercules Wheel, "Type D", 1920; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 11: View of Everett Mills 39" Hercules Wheel, "Type D", 1920; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 12: View of Everett Mills Wheel No. 2, "G" 27" R. H. Hercules, 1920; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 13: View of Everett Mills Wheel No. 2, "G" 27" R. H. Hercules, 1920; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 14: View of Everett Mills Wheel No. 2, "G" 27" R. H. Hercules, 1920; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 15: View of Everett Mills 39" Hercules Wheel, "Type D", 1920; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 16: View of Everett Mills Wheel No. 2, "G" 27" R. H. Hercules, 1920; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 17: View of Everett Mills Wheel No. 2, "G" 27" R. H. Hercules, 1920; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 18: View of Everett Mills Wheel No. 2, "G" 27" R. H. Hercules, 1920; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 19: View of Washington Mills 45" Type D Hercules Wheel, 1922; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
    November 11, 1922.
  - Item 20: View of Washington Mills 45" Type D Hercules Wheel, 1922; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 21: View of Washington Mills 45" Type D Hercules Wheel, 1922; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 22: View of Washington Mills 45" Type D Hercules Wheel, 1922; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 23: View of Washington Mills 45" Type D Hercules Wheel, R. H. Guides, 1922; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 24: View of Washington Mills 45" Type D Hercules Wheel, R. H. Guides, 1922; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 25: View of Washington Mills 45" Type D L. H. Hercules Wheel, 1922; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
    November 10, 1922.
  - Item 26: View of Washington Mills 33 in. L. H. Hercules Wheel, 1922; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
    May 12, 1899.
  - Item 27: View of Washington Mills 33 in. L. H. Hercules Wheel, 1922; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 28: View of Washington Mills Co. Wheel No. 3, cone and draft tube, 1898; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
    Taken on car near main gate. Feb. 12, 1898.
  - Item 29: View of Lower Pacific Mills Wheel, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
    ca. 1900
  - Item 30: View of Lower Pacific Mills Wheel, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 31: View of Lower Pacific Mills Wheel, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 32: View of Lower Pacific Mills 56 in. R. H. Leffel Wheel, 1923; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
    April 20, 1923.
  - Item 33: View of Lower Pacific Mills Wheel No. 2, 1915; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
    April 7, 1915.
  - Item 34: View of Lower Pacific Mills Wheel No. 2, 1915; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 35: View of Lower Pacific Mills Wheel No. 2, 1915; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 36: View of Lower Pacific Mills Wheel No. 2, 1915; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 37: View of Lower Pacific Mills 56 in. R. H. Leffel Wheel, 1923; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 38: View of Lower Pacific Mills 56 in. R. H. Leffel Wheel, 1923; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 39: View of Pemberton Company Wheel, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
    ca. 1920
  - Item 40: View of Pemberton Company 43 in. R. H. Type, Leffel Wheel, 1921; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
    May 3, 1921.
  - Item 41: View of Pemberton Company 43 in. R. H. Type, Leffel Wheel, 1921; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 42: View of Pemberton Company 43 in. R. H. Type, Leffel Wheel, 1921; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 43: View of Pemberton Company 43 in. R. H. Type, Leffel Wheel, 1921; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 44: View of Pemberton Company Wheel No. 3, Drat Tube, 1921; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 45: View of Pemberton Company Wheel No. 3, Drat Tube, 1921; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 46: View of Pemberton Company Wheel No. 3, Drat Tube, 1921; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 47: View of Pemberton Company Wheel Guides, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 48: View of Pemberton Company Wheel Guides, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 49: View of Pemberton Company Wheel Guides, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 50: View of Pemberton Company Wheel, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 51: View of Pemberton Company 43 in. R. H. Type, Leffel Wheel, 1921; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 52: View of Pemberton Company 43 in. R. H. Type, Leffel Wheel, 1921; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 53: View of Pemberton Company Wheel No. 2, 39" R. H. Hercules Class A, 1917; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
    August 25, 1917.
  - Item 54: View of Pemberton Company 43 in. R. H. Type, Leffel Wheel, 1921; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 55: View of Lawrence Gas & Electric Co. New No. 3 Wheel, 1927; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
    September 22, 1927.
  - Item 56: View of Lawrence Gas & Electric Co. New No. 3 Wheel, 1927; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 57: View of Lawrence Gas & Electric Co. New No. 3 Wheel, 1927; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 58: View of Lawrence Gas & Electric Co. Draft Tube No. 5, 1905; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
    August 24, 1905.
  - Item 59: View of Lawrence Gas & Electric Co. Draft Tube No. 5, 1905; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 60: View of Lawrence Gas & Electric Co. Draft Tube No. 5, 1905; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 61: View of Lawrence Gas & Electric Co. Draft Tube No. 5, 1905; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 62: View of E. Frank Lewis 26 in. L. H. Leffel Wheel, 1923; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
    February 1923.
  - Item 63: View of E. Frank Lewis 26 in L. H. Leffel G...?, 1923; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 64: View of E. Frank Lewis 26 in L. H. Leffel G...?, 1923; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 65: View of Munroe Felt & Paper Co. 33 in. L. H. Hercules Wheel, 1907; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
    July 9, 1907.
  - Item 66: View of Munroe Felt & Paper Co. Hercules Wheel, 1896; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
    September 12, 1896.
  - Item 67: View of F. E. Chandler 26 in. Leffel Wheel, 1898; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
    June 20, 1898.
  - Item 68: View of F. E. Chandler 26 in. Leffel Wheel, 1898; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 69: View of Farwell Bleachery 24 in. L. H. McCormick Wheel, 1910; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
    On a Central Vermont R.R. flatcar, October 14, 1910.
  - Item 70: View of Farwell Bleachery 36 inch Swain turbine, 1895; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
    December 31, 1895.
  - Item 71: View of Farwell Bleachery 36 inch Swain turbine, 1895; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 72: View of Lawrence Duck Co., 1900; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
    48 in. R. H. N. S. Hor. Hercules Wheel No. 2, Nvember 14, 1900
  - Item 73: View of S. Morgan Smith Co. turbine/wheel, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 74: View of Atlantic Cotton Mills, 1908; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 1)
    R. H. 48 in. Hercules Wheel, Lawrence, Mass., August 20, 1908
- P 217.346-.437 -- Boston and Lowell RR Bridge, Short St. Bridge, Plymouth Mills; Lower Pacific Mills; Duck Bridge; miscellaneous photographs, 1896-1967 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: View of Spicket River, 1897; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
    Short Street Bridge Looking Easterly, June, 1897
  - Item 2: View of Spicket River, 1897; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
    Short Street Bridge Looking West, June, 1897
  - Item 3: View of Spicket River, 1897; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 4: View of Spicket River, 1897; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 5: View of Essex Co's North Canal looking Easterly on Canal Street, 1897; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
    Showing Fence and Tow path to Right, June, 1897
  - Item 6: View of Saunders house, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
    Boys playing at pump in foreground
  - Item 7: View of Essex Company's North Canal, 1897; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
    Boston and Lowell R.R. Bridge from Tow path looking East, June 1897
  - Item 8: View of Essex Company's North Canal, 1897; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
    Boston and Lowell R.R. Bridge looking Easterly from Tow path, June 1897
  - Item 9: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 10: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 11: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 12: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 13: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 14: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 15: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 16: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 17: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 18: View of "New Pit Floors", 1913; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
    Plymouth Mills, August 1, 1913
  - Item 19: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 20: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 21: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 22: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 23: View of Spicket River below Globe Dam, 1902; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 24: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 25: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 26: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 27: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 28: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 29: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 30: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 31: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 32: View of Spicket River below Globe Dam, 1902; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 33: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 34: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 35: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 36: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 37: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 38: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 39: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 40: View of River from Sulphur Bleaching House, 1896; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
    Lower Pacific Mills, freshet of 1896
  - Item 41: View of River from Sulphur Bleaching House, 1896; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
    Lower Pacific Mills, 3h-30m P.M. March 2, 1896. Lower Pacific Mills Gage=29.80
  - Item 42: Unidentified exterior view of bridge, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 43: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 44: North Andover Sewer outlet 2' pipe, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
    Just east of mouth of Shawsheen River. Ret. bottom of outlet=2.18
  - Item 45: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 46: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 47: View of portion of Duck Bridge, 1904; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
    Union Street
  - Item 48: View of portion of Duck Bridge, 1904; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 49: View of portion of Duck Bridge, 1904; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 50: View of portion of Duck Bridge, 1904; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 51: View of portion of Duck Bridge, 1904; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 52: View of portion of Duck Bridge, 1904; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 53: View of portion of Duck Bridge, 1904; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 54: View of portion of Duck Bridge, 1904; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 55: View of River from Lower Pacific Mill No. 4, 1896; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
    2h-30m P.M. March 3, 1896, freshet of 1896
  - Item 56: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 57: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 58: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 59: View of rear of Lower Pacific Mills, 1896; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
    Merrimack River, Lawrence, 3h-30m P.M. March 2, 1896- L.P. Gauge=29.80 rising
  - Item 60: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 61: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 62: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 63: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 64: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 65: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 66: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 67: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 68: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 69: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 70: View of Lower lock gate, North Canal, 1903; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
    February 1903.
  - Item 71: View of Lower lock gate, North Canal, 1903; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 72: View of Penstock Headgate apparatus, Champion International, 1925; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
    November 1925.
  - Item 73: View of Lower lock gate, North Canal, 1903; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 74: View of penstock, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 75: View of lock gate, 1903; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 76: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 77: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 78: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 79: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 80: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 81: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 82: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 83: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 84: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 85: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 86: View of Essex Street, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
    Holy Rosary Church at right
  - Item 87: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 88: View of sewer construction, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 89: Unidentified view of Holyoke, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 90: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 91: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 92: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 2)
- P 217.563-.573 -- Everett Mill; Essex Co. Bldg.; Mitchells Falls; miscellaneous photographs, 1897-1910 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: View of Head of Mitchells Falls, Merrimack River, 1897; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 3)
    Lower end of Kimballs Island on right, Ward Hill Hotel in distance, October 3, 1897.
  - Item 2: View of Mitchells Falls, Merrimack River, 1897; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 3)
    Bed of River looking up stream. Pool is opposite Gauge No. 4. Kimball's Island on the extreme right, October 3, 1897.
  - Item 3: View of Mitchells Falls, Merrimack River, 1897; black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 3)
    Showing channel in upper falls, October 3, 1897.
  - Item 4: View shows people walking across railroad bridge, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Item 5: Unidentified exterior view, black and white photograph (Box 15, Folder 3)